welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial with the free software kdenlive
免费软件kdenlive的教程
in this video I just want to show you a
在这段视频中 我只是想向你们展示一个
couple cool resources that you might
组合一些很酷的资源 你可能会
have been aware of in kdenlive
已经意识到在kdenlive
the first thing is let's say we have a
第一件事是假设我们有一个
video clip let's grab in I'll just go
视频剪辑让我们抓紧时间 我要走了
add clip and let's bring in one of these
添加剪辑 让我们引入其中一个
ones we've used before like this cyclist
我们以前用过的 像这个自行车手
video and so we'll just click here to
视频 所以我们只需点击此处
zoom in so this video doesn't have any
放大以使此视频没有任何
audio so let's say we wanted to put in
所以假设我们想要放入音频
like a sound effect at a certain point
就像某一时刻的音效
in this video like when he's like
在这段视频中 他就像是
grabbing the bike or right when he's
抓起自行车 或者就在他
about to write off so if we wanted like
即将注销 所以如果我们想要
a I don't know what the sound would be
A我不知道会是什么声音
but instead of going we can go to like
但我们可以去 而不是去
freesound.org or we can go record our
或者我们可以去录制我们的
own sound but we can find some online
自己的声音 但我们可以在网上找到一些
but also kdenlive has built-in options
但Kdenlive也有内置选项
if we go to project we can go to online
如果我们去项目 我们就可以去网上
resources right here so under project
资源就在这里 所以在项目下
online resources it brings up this
在线资源它带来了这一点
dialog box I think we can also do it by
对话框我想我们也可以通过
clicking this triangle here yeah and
点击这里的这个三角形 是的 还有
then we go to online resources and so
然后我们转到在线资源 所以
there's a couple different as of the
到目前为止 有几个不同的
recording of this video there's three
录制这段视频有三个
different options we can search for
我们可以搜索不同的选项
clipart which is going to be like vector
剪贴画 它将像矢量一样
graphics and like just steal pictures of
图片 就像偷照片一样
usually like cartoony looking pictures
通常喜欢卡通形象的照片
we can do archive.org video library and
我们可以制作档案网站的视频库和
any of these places we can just go to
这些地方中的任何一个我们都可以去
directly as well
也可以直接使用
well this clip arts a collection of
嗯 这张剪贴画收集了
places I think and there's free sound
我认为有免费声音的地方
audio library and so so if we if we want
音频库 所以如果我们想要
to find a sound effect for this we can
为了找到音效 我们可以
even type we can even find music we just
甚至打字 我们甚至可以找到音乐 我们只是
type in music or maybe we type in jazz
输入音乐或者我们输入爵士乐
if you want a certain type of music it
如果你想要某种类型的音乐
brings up all these different options
提出了所有这些不同的选项
for files and it says here so this is
文件 这里写着 所以这是
the duration of this is 15 seconds long
此过程的持续时间为15秒
there's a couple different ones here
这里有几个不同的
this one's three and a half seconds long
这个有三秒半长
this is more jazz so let's do this 15
这是更多的爵士乐 所以让我们做这个15
second one so we can actually click
第二个 所以我们可以实际点击
preview to listen to it and see what it
预览以收听并查看内容
sounds like
听起来像是
cool so if we like that we can actually
很好 如果我们喜欢这样 我们实际上可以
just click import and it says where do
只需单击导入 系统会显示在何处执行
you want to save it on your computer
您想要将其保存在您的计算机上
will say save it under music we'll call
会说在音乐下保存它 我们会叫它
it yeah more jazz guitar dot mp3 click
它是的更多爵士吉他点mp3点击
Save and then it just is right there on
保存 然后它就会出现在那里
our computer
我们的电脑
it actually downloads it and saves it
它实际上会下载并保存它
and brings it in to our as a resource we
并把它作为一种资源带到我们的
can use in our project bin that's pretty
可以在我们的项目垃圾箱中使用 很漂亮
cool huh and then we can just drag it
很酷 嗯 然后我们就可以拖着它了
down and now we have this music we can
现在我们有了这首音乐 我们可以
play in our project pretty cool huh
参与我们的项目很酷吧？
and then if we wanted something to we
如果我们想要什么 我们就
can grab if we want to play with green
如果我们想玩绿色游戏 可以抓住
screen or for example we can go to back
屏幕 或者例如 我们可以返回到
to the online resources we can go down
到我们可以下载的在线资源
to well we can go to the video yeah
我们可以去看录像带是的
video library when you just type in
录入时的视频库
green screen maybe we want a video that
绿屏也许我们想要一个视频
has green screen we click search and it
有绿色屏幕 我们点击搜索 然后它
has all these different options now
现在有所有这些不同的选择
these we can't preview at least not
这些我们不能预览 至少不能
within here to look at it like this
在这里 这样看待它
North I'm not sure which was we got here
北边 我不确定我们到了哪边
we'll find one that we think might be
我们会找到一个我们认为可能是
like pixie green screen it tells a
就像小精灵绿色屏幕一样 它告诉我们
little bit about it and if we have all
稍微了解一下 如果我们都
the different options for how we can
我们可以选择不同的方式
import it they can be flash MPEG oh gee
导入他们可以是闪存的mpeg哦天
geez we got these different options and
天哪 我们有这么多不同的选择
also has the license down here so this
也在这下面有执照 所以这个
ins we have to provide attribution to
我们必须向他们提供身份证明
the person that created it which it'll
创造它的人 它将
say not sure where it says it we can go
说不确定它说我们能去哪里
to the website to find out and we can
到网站上去找出答案 我们可以
not use it for commercial purposes and
不得将其用于商业目的
it's under a share alike license but
它是在类似股份的许可证下 但
they have different licenses so they'll
他们有不同的执照 所以他们会
tell you and in fact that we should
告诉你 事实上 我们应该
looked at that one that we used that J
看着我们用的那个J
Deb jazz here oops
Deb爵士乐在这里哦哦
search we go back to find the one that
寻找我们回去寻找的那个人
we used so that one was under Creative
我们使用了 所以其中一个在Creative项下
Commons 0 so it's just very very open we
公地0 所以我们非常非常开放
can use it for commercial purposes a
可以将其用于商业目的
null attribute required but a different
需要空属性 但不同
ones have different so this is
它们有不同之处 所以这是
attribution non-commercial if you're not
如果您不是非商业性的 则归因于
familiar with the Creative Commons
熟悉知识共享空间
licenses I have I made a video about
我有执照 我拍了一段视频
that so you can check that out and learn
这样你就可以查看并学习
about with the difference license types
关于不同的许可类型
but just make sure you always understand
但你要确保你总是明白
just because you can download something
仅仅因为你可以下载一些东西
off the internet doesn't mean it's
不在互联网上并不意味着
completely free to use for any purpose
完全免费 可用于任何目的
you always have to check with what the
你总是要检查什么是
the author or the creator that has
作者或创造者拥有
allowed for those purposes to be used
允许为这些目的而使用
for let's see what else okay so we've
让我们看看还有什么好的 所以我们已经
got a clipart let's let's look at
有剪贴画 让我们来看看
clipart and we don't wanna search jazz
我们不想搜索爵士乐
on clipart we want to search whatever we
在剪贴画上 我们想搜索任何我们想要的东西
want to do me we want to do oh so it did
想做我 我们想做 哦 就是这样做了
jazz actually I don't know we can do
爵士乐其实我不知道我们能不能
like a head and so it searches finds all
就像一个头 所以它搜索找到了所有
these different things for hat and then
帽子的这些不同的东西 然后
we can go through and look and we can
我们可以穿过去 看一看 我们可以
look at though this is a public domain
尽管这是一个公共领域 但请看
police stop so we can be okay and if we
警察停下来 这样我们就可以没事了 如果我们
click the link we follow the link it'll
点击链接 我们将点击该链接
actually bring it up in the web browser
实际上是在Web浏览器中调出它
and we can look and see this is what it
我们可以看到这就是它
looks like and then we can just download
看起来是这样 然后我们就可以下载
it from here
从这里开始
or we could download it we can just
或者我们可以下载它 我们可以
click down the import here and I'll say
点击此处的导入按钮 我会说
where do you want to save it maybe we'll
你想把它放在哪里？也许我们可以
put it under our pictures folder call it
把它放在我们的图片文件夹下 叫它
police stop and this is an SVG image so
警察停了下来 这是一张SVG图像
now it's there it's brought in now we
现在它在那里它被带进来了现在我们
can bring it in and we could either have
可以把它带进来 我们可以
it be as part of our video we can just
作为我们视频的一部分 我们可以
play it and we can't see it because it's
播放它 我们看不到它 因为它是
a black background or we can overlay it
一个黑色背景 或者我们可以覆盖它
over top here to the so now we've got
从这里到现在我们已经有了
like this overlay yeah anyway that's
像这样的叠加 对 不管怎么说 这是
what I want to show you is these free
我想向你们展示的是这些免费的
resources then also and this isn't
资源也是如此 而这不是
working for me I think it's because I'm
为我工作我想是因为我
using a portable version on Windows but
在Windows上使用便携版本 但
this should work for you on Linux if you
这在Linux上应该可以工作 如果您
over the settings here where was it at
在这里的设置上 它是在哪里
you can go to download so we can
你可以去下载这样我们就可以
download new wipes so we can get all
下载新的湿巾 这样我们就可以
kinds of different effects for wipes we
各种不同效果的纸巾我们
have all these different ones we can
我们可以拥有所有这些不同的
just look at look at it see what it does
看看它 看看它做了什么
so like for like transitions wipes we
所以像这样的过渡擦去了我们
can also do we can download new title
我们还可以下载新书
templates and there's only a few of
模板 并且只有几个
these right now as of the recording of
这些都是截至录制的
this video but this could expand in the
这个视频 但这可能会在
future and if you're interested in
如果你对未来感兴趣
contributing you might be able to even
贡献给你也许能让你
create some and then submit them as a
创建一些 然后将其作为
change since kdenlive is an open-source
更改 因为kdenlive是一个开放源码
project you can potentially could
您可以潜在地
contribute to this software and create
贡献于此软件并创建
your own add-on templates to be added
要添加的您自己的附加组件模板
into the software but anyway these are
但不管怎样这些都是
some different ones that we can you can
一些不同的 我们可以 你可以
download
下载
and just shows you kind of what they are
只是向你展示了它们是什么
and you can go to the website and
你可以去网站上
download and install them that way or
以这种方式下载并安装它们 或者
you can just do it from within the
您只需在
software just click install and
软件只需点击安装和
uninstall all right well that is I think
卸载很好 我想就是这样
what I wanted to show you also if you
我想向你们展示的是 如果你们
need help there's like this we've got
需要帮助 就像这样 我们得到了帮助
the kdenlive handbook under help it just
正在帮助下的Kdenlive手册只是
goes and there's all kinds of different
去了 那里有各种各样不同的
if you're wondering about rendering
如果您想知道如何渲染
there's some difference you know some
有一些不同 你知道一些
information here and again you could
这里的信息你可以一次又一次
contribute to this and actually help
为此做出贡献 并真正提供帮助
improve this resource as well but just a
也要改进这个资源 但只是一个
couple things I found when I was you
当我是你的时候 我发现了几件事
know kind of looking through some of the
我知道我在看一些
different options here that I've failed
不同的选择 我失败了
to mention in some of the earlier videos
在之前的一些视频中提到
hopefully you found this video
希望你找到了这段视频
informative go ahead and like the
内容丰富 请继续 并喜欢
subscribe comment below and I'll catch
订阅下面的评论 我会赶上的
you in the next video
下一个视频中的你